Luis Miguel Palacio Restrepo

Barcelona, Catalonia, Spain



luis@palaciorestrepo.com



+34 618380017



linkedin.com/in/Impalacio

Summary

Passionate for interactive and immersive systems, curious for emergent technologies and innovative solutions that evoke multiple emotions to create memorable experiences; mostly on projects leaned on entertainment and cognitive systems.

Since the school, manifested interest in Engineering and Design; surrounded by a family of engineers with pragmatic solutions but also a very creative mother that motivated him to practice abilities such as drawing and divergent thinking to understand real-life situations from diverse perspectives. Therefore, a mixed profile between computer science and design has been built, adding tools such as programming, electronics, and agile methodologies to approach multidisciplinary projects.

My years training traditional kung fu taught me that knowledge and wisdom can be found everywhere, thereby we should consider ourselves masters but also eternal apprentices. Then, I found that my competitive spirit and empathy helped me to improve soft skills through online videogames and become a better team player capable to lead my partners into victory.

Experience



Innovation Developer

TODO1 Services

Aug 2018 - Aug 2019 (1 year 1 month)

The role required constant exploration, which allowed the business to understand around 10 different technologies through fast prototyping followed by Scrum-based methodology, user testing, and some internal presentations as a strategy to expand the knowledge across the company. That research was guided by a trend radar that we built and kept updated constantly.

1

Apprentice of Innovation

TODO1 Services

Feb 2018 - Aug 2018 (7 months)

Multiple applications focused on the financial sector were developed. Implementation and deployment of virtual assistants/chatbots on Facebook Messenger and Skype For Business, development of mobile applications and participation in projects from their early stages of conceptualization until its minimu viable product definition.

System Software Developer

PikPok S.A.S (Antes Wizard Fun Factory)

Sep 2017 - Sep 2017 (1 month)

Implementation of an interactive system with reactive lights and sensors of presence; integrating a simple protocol to send information from Arduino to an Unity3D application.

Education



upf. Universitat Pompeu Fabra

Master in Cognitive Systems and Interactive Media 2019 - 2020

Universidad Pontificia Bolivariana

Ingeniería en Diseño de Entretenimiento Digital, Engineering 2014 - 2018

Skills

Innovación tecnológica • Engineering • Interactive Media • Electronics • Programación • Project Management • Mobile Applications • Product Innovation • Video Games • Design Thinking

Honors & Awards



GLOBAL GAME JAM 2016 - The Global Game Jam

Jan 2016

Participation with the game Oniric Dash

🚮 GLOBAL GAME JAM 2017 - The Global Game Jam

Jan 2017

Participation and recognition as best use of hardware with the game Samsong. Made with Unity and Arduino.

COSTA RICAN CENTER OF SCIENCE AND CULTUR - Centro Costarricense de

Ciencia y Cultura

2017

Participation in the multidisciplinary project: Interactive experiences inside the child's museum of Costa Rica.

GLOBAL GAME JAM 2019 - The Global Game Jam

Jan 2019

Participation with the game Hobo Fight!

INDIE PRIZE USA 2019 FINALIST

Aug 2019

Participation and recognition with the game "Hobo Flght!", developed with Unity and born in the Global Game Jam 2019.